







Rahul Sangale

TCG apartment, Hinjewadi ph2, Pune 7021354538 rahulssangale@gmail.com

RAHUL SANGALE

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A meticulous and technically astute IT Professional with over 5 years of pioneering experience in virtualization by **VMware and Cloud services** with comprehensive knowledge and understanding of **Microsoft Azure**, **AWS**, **Google Cloud**. Seeking to prove and utilize my skills effectively and efficiently to provide impetus to my career in the process of achieving organizational goals in Information Technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Cloud Services Azure, AWS, GCP
- VMware, ESXI, VCenter, PowerCli, vSphere, CWOM
- Cisco UCS, Nutanix, HP
- Windows Server administration
- Python
- ITSM through Service now
- Network: Http, SSL, SFTP, TCP, DNS, DHCP
- Microsoft certified Azure administrator (AZ-104)
- Microsoft certified azure architect technologies (AZ-303)
- Google Certified cloud associate engineer.
- Google certified professional cloud architect

EXPERIENCE

TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

INFOSYS LTD

JAN 2019 -PRESENT

experience in system architect, administrator with years of experience. architecture /design and deployment solution using VMware and cloud service like -AWS/azure. Working knowledge of AWS/Azure, VMware, ESXI, Windows Server, Nutanix, Cisco UCS.

Cloud:

- Perform POC for azure and AWS services for client and provide report which help them to finalize Cloud solution.
- Migrated the on-premises workloads to Azure &AWS cloud based on the requirement.
- Provides design, development, testing, maintenance, delivery and support for the full life cycle of activities related to Systems and subscriptions in Azure Cloud environment.
- Experience in creating azure service like VM, blob, vnet, DB.
- Migrated the on-premises workloads to Azure cloud based on the requirement.
- Deploy configure and maintain compute, storage & network services of Azure cloud
- Design and deploy Azure Backup and other Confidential backup solutions for Azure
- Responsible for systems and application performance monitoring.

- Build of new environments for development and test in Azure.
- Infrastructure as code using ARM and terraform
- Firsthand experience with most layer of AWS offering.
- Involved in designing and deploying a multitude application utilizing almost all of the AWS stack (Including EC2, Route53, S3, RDS, Dynamo DB, SNS, SQS, IAM) focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Configured Security groups for EC2 instances
- Created users and groups using IAM and assigned individual policies to each group.
- experience in backup services like EBS snapshots, S3 backups and Amazon Glacier
- Create and manage \$3 buckets
- Create snapshots and AMI for cloning.

Virtualization:

- Excellent experience and knowledge with designing installing and implementing virtualization environment with VMware ESXi, VMware virtual center, setting up V-Motion, HA, DRS.
- Fresh installation of ESXI host in different hardware.
- administration, installation and support of VMware, Cisco UCS technology server hardware
- Provide **L3 support for VMware** environment. Troubleshoot critical issues.
- Expertise on ESXi and ESX Architecture, guest OS installation, setting up of VM priorities, Cloning and Snapshots, Cold Migrations and Hot Migrations. Creating Templates from VM's, deploy VM's from templates and allocate resources
- Providing and maintaining user access in vCenter server and maintenance of vCenter server
- Support daily monitoring and optimization of VM servers and ESXi hosts in production, dev and Test environment.
- Planning &Perform **patching of VMware** environment
- Do capacity management using tool Turbonomic CWOM and create automated task for rightsizings VMs and cluster.
- Create script using VMware powerCli to automate task in VMware.

Cisco UCS & Nutanix:

- Firsthand experience on Hardware like Cisco UCS B/C blade, Nutanix and troubleshoot, debug, diagnose issue in nutanix and cisco UCS
- **Upgraded** UCS domain **firmware** ver. from 2.2(3f) to 3.1(1e).
- Worked on Cisco UCS Manager, UCS Central to build service profile and templates.
- Created service profiles and template in cisco UCS for new blade installations.
- Installation of nutanix and install ESXI on that and Mange nutanix clusters to stay healthy
- Performed upgradation of UCS and nutanix versions and firmware.
- Mange Nutanix installation and cluster configuration.
- Troubleshoot issues related to nutanix HW, Prism central.
- Keep Cisco UCS and nutanix HW healthy and running.

RELIANCE INDUSTRIES LIMITED

OCT 2017 -DEC 2018

WORKING AS SERVER MANAGER AT RELIANCE INDUSTRIES LIMITED ON PAYROLL OF CMS IT SERVICES

- Creating and Managing the Virtual machines. Working with Templates and Clones
 & Deploying Virtual Machine from Templates.
- Installation, Configuration, Administration and Troubleshooting of ESX 6.0, Vcenter.
- Administration of enterprise-sized VMware-based virtualization infrastructures covering vCenter and standalone ESXi environments version 5.5 & later
- Installing, configuring and integrating servers associated with a VMware virtual infrastructure
- Health Check for Virtual Machines and ESXi host.
- Migration of Operating systems/servers, Migrating the Virtual Machines from one host to another host by using Motion technique. Working on VMware clustering like HA and DRS clusters using Virtual Center.
- Creating resources pool, Template & Clone in Virtual Center.
- Perform regular system maintenance, backups and software upgrades.
- Designed and deployed a virtual domain network for use as a development environment that includes domain controller, Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, and a Microsoft Exchange server
- Installing, Configuring of Windows 2008 / 2012 /2016/2019 Server OS and linux.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing AD / DHCP / DNS / IIS / File Server / Print Server.
- Perform windows patching activity on all servers.
- Managing and troubleshooting of Microsoft DNS, DHCP, DFS. NTFS-Permissions planning and configuration for the end users on the file servers and quota assignment and management
- Print Server: Configuring and troubleshooting of print servers and web-based printers.
- Co-ordinating with the hardware vendors like Dell, HP & Orange Business Services for manual intervention and replacement of faulty hardware of the servers.
- Utilize Windows Server Update Services to manage and deploy software patches.
- administrator for Microsoft SCOM monitoring tool. Configure Event ID in SCOM for different group of servers
- SCOM platform and create and maintain monitoring and notification rules.
- Handling Active directory services as Admin. perform L2 level task in AD
- Managed User Accounts (Creation, Deletion, Permissions, and VPN Access).
- Perform cleaning activity on Active Directory and Creation of groups, objects in AD.

.

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGG

VALUEPOINT SYSTEMS PVT LTD

JULY-2017 — OCT-2017

- Functioning as L1 Server administrator r which takes care of complete IT infrastructure
- Active directory Administration (user Administration). Create and Modify AD accounts.
- Troubleshoot Server Performance related issue.
- Implement network traffic and security monitoring software and optimize server performance.
- Install, maintain, troubleshoot and upgrade workstation / server hardware and operating system version.

- Troubleshooting of the servers for which alerts were generated by the monitoring software and performing daily checks.
- Create testing virtual environment for development Team.
- Managing, Maintaining and Administering WSUS Server 3.0 for Patch Management WSUS server administration (Patches Installation).
- Managing Group Policies, Creation of user mailbox,
- Maintaining Symantec Endpoint security console
- User account creation, mailbox creation, email forwarding, Microsoft outlook calendar access, delegation access, shared mailboxes, distribution list, and termination of mailboxes on Exchange Server 2013 server and Active Directory.
- Policies. Created and maintained email addresses and distribution lists in MS Exchange. Perform cleaning activity on Active Directory and Creation of groups, objects in AD.

DESKTOP ENGINEER LEVEL 2 WIPRO (PAYROLL -APEX SERVICES) NOV-2015 — JUNE-2017

- Core IT Handling Client Ernst & Young Pvt. Ltd. Functioning as Remote Engineer coordinator which takes care of complete local IT infrastructure
- Mange VMware Workstations Creation. Modification of WIN 7 machines.
- Trouble shooting issues of VMware win 7 machines.
- Mange 5 Level 1 engineers on site.
- Monitoring call productivity of engineers and helpdesk team. Handling VIP calls and resolve within SLA.
- Managing of user accounts, groups and other network resources on Active Directory Services2008/2012.
- Escalate incidents and tasks to the appropriate personnel as needed.
- Lotus notes (8 & 9) and Outlook client version trouble shooting. Lotus ID creation and configuration and troubleshooting.
- Deployment of WIN XP and Win7 to all PC's with customized image.
- Giving best support for more than 1000 Laptops which are used in company for project purpose which is sprayed all over India also taking care of IT asset used by client employees. Call logging through Service Now IT service management tool.
- Administration of RSA secure ID servers for login and authentication issues.
- Administration of Good Mobile Messaging server for android, iOS devices and BlackBerry server for BlackBerry OS 10 and below devices.
- Provide Wi-Fi access on mobile devices & laptop based on MAC address.

CERTIFICATIO NS

- AWS certified cloud practitioner
- Microsoft certified azure administrator associate (AZ-104)
- Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer
- Microsoft certified azure architect technologies (AZ-303)
- · Google certified professional cloud architect

EDUCATION

B.E Computer 2011 — 2015

K.K Wagh College of Engineering Education and Research

Completed Graduation in Bachelor of engineering in first class in 2015

HSC 2009 — 2011

RLT College of science, Akola

Secure 85% in HSC

SSC 2008 — 2009

Dr patil high School, Akola

Secure 85% in HSC